<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iOS on Accessibility → Up to 11!</title>
    <link>https://dadederk.github.io/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iOS on Accessibility → Up to 11!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadederk.github.io/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of iOS Accessibility</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2024-12-06-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2024-12-06-01/</guid>
      <description>Advent of iOS Accessibility Starting something new: The Advent of iOS Accessibility. Twenty-four days of exploring some of the most common accessibility issues I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered, how to identify them, and—most importantly—how to fix them. Hope you enjoy the series!
Day 1 One of the accessibility issues I see more often in iOS apps, believe it or not, is unlabelled elements. This happens especially for buttons with an icon but no title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building accessible mobile apps</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-08-31-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-08-31-01/</guid>
      <description>Title: Best practices for building accessible mobile apps Increment Magazine - Issue 18, about all things mobile, is out now! And I&amp;rsquo;m really honoured they&amp;rsquo;ve let me be part of it! Please check out my article: &amp;ldquo;Best practices for building accessible mobile apps&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you think! I hope you like it!
Description: An overview of the mindset, strategies, and tools that will help you create apps that truly work for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing iOS Apps with an Accessibility Mindset</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-08-26-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-08-26-01/</guid>
      <description>Title: Developing iOS Apps with an Accessibility Mindset My talk from CocoaHeads NL.
Description: Accessibility should part of the job for any developer. But as user can have very diverse disabilities it can be challenging to know what features the platform has available for them and how to use them effectively. Dani explores the API&amp;rsquo;s and highlights features like VoiceOver, Switch Control and VoiceControl.
Youtube Video:   Tweets: How cool is this sketchnote by Felizia Bernutz perfectly summarising the content of the talk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a good accessible iOS app</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-01-21-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2021-01-21-01/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published in Medium
You may know that you can configure a UI component with an accessibility label. The accessibility label is the name of the component. You can also configure an accessibility trait. The accessibility trait is the role of the component, it gives the user information on how they can interact with it. When using VoiceOver, the trait is usually vocalised after the accessibility label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessible iOS Apps: Up To 11!</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2020-10-23-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2020-10-23-01/</guid>
      <description>My talk from #a11yTo Conf.
To celebrate, Apress is offering a 20% discount in my book &amp;ldquo;Developing Accessible iOS Apps&amp;rdquo; with the code &amp;lsquo;a11yTOConf&amp;rsquo; in their website. Valid till October 30, 2020.
Description: Let’s go on a journey to create, not just accessible iOS apps, but awesome accessible experiences that absolutely all your users will be able to use and love. How do we bring VoiceOver&amp;rsquo;s support to the next level?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for testing your iOS app’s accessibility</title>
      <link>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2020-08-11-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dadederk.github.io/post/2020-08-11-01/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published in Medium
The cycle for creating great accessible apps starts and ends with testing. Sure, it is always better to get feedback from users to create an experience that holds up to their expectations. But that’s not always possible. Till you can do it, I think the way to go is to do your best. Build it as well as you can, then gather all the feedback you can get, apply the suggestions, test, repeat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
